Andrea McKenzie

mckenzie.andrea.m@gmail.com

917 674 6154

https://github.com/SiouxsieAsylum

Currently undergoing General Assembly's Web Development Immersion to learn Node.js, React.js, and the Express.js framework as well as Ruby and/on Rails. I have a singular passion for Android that has lead me to learn Java and how to utilize it on the Android framework. Before studying Web Development, I was an experienced retail buyer with 6+ years of customer service experience in a food and beverage/grocery environment and 2+ years of supervisory experience. Proficient in managing purchasing and supply budgets while still employing a keen eye for in-demand products and merchandising design. Graduated Cum Laude with a Bachelors of Arts in English from CUNY Hunter in 2013.

Projects:

Bellydance by Layla,

HTML5, CSS3, Javascript
Desktop-only client commission
Responsive design coming soon
https://siouxsieasylum.github
.io/Bellydancing-By-Layla/

Dissonance

HTML5, CSS3, Javascript
Desktop-only based upon the
Stroop test.
Responsive. Mobile support
coming soon.
https://siouxsieasylum.github
.io/Dissonance/

Wine By Dre

.io/Wine-By-Dre

React
Responsive React application built to emulate a wine store.
https://siouxsieasylum.github

Experience:

Perscholas: Bronx, NY Front-End Web Developer August 2017 - October 2017

Developed and maintained static websites with varying levels of interactiveness, size, and complexity. Cultivated an eye for UX/UI design. Mastered the new features of HTML5 and CSS3, and learned proper file structure, best practices, and how to integrate APIs.

Whole Foods Market: Various Locations

Specialty Beer Buyer/Equipment Purchaser

Sept 2013 - August 2017

Directly coordinated orders with distributors to maximize accuracy and negotiate prices to maximize profit margin. Maximized and streamlined interdepartmental and vertical communication for sake of team satisfaction and efficiency. Worked directly with store and regional leadership to troubleshoot, fix and clean broken growler lines. Recognized by Regional Leadership as a rescuer and maintainer of financially failing subteams.

AGRION Inc.: Remote

Market Report Writer Feb 2014-Sept 2014

Performed market research and wrote analytical, concise snapshots of marketing reports on cutting-edge clean energy, clean tech, and sustainability issues, including weekly roundtable discussions. Reports cover a wide range of topics including renewable energy, green buildings, green data centers, energy storage, and corporate sustainability.

Education:

General Assembly: 2017Web Development Immersive

PerScholas: 2017 #Codebridge

Self-Taught 2yrs

Hunter College: 2013 B.A. in English *Cum Laude*

Proficiencies:

- ♦ CSS3 Animations and transitions
- ♦ React & React Router
- ◆ Node.js w/Express framework (Beginner-Intermediate)
- ◆ Ruby on Rails (Beginner-Intermediate)
- ♦ 6+ years in customer relations
- ♦ 3+ years vendor relations